Afan Ahmed

(+64) 2041400988 ahmed.afanami@gmail.com Auckland 0614, New Zealand <u>afanahmed.me</u> <u>github.com/Afanami</u> linkedin.com/in/afanahmed

I am a Graduate Mechatronics Engineering student from The University of Auckland who is passionate about technology and frontend development. I have a demonstrated high drive for learning by being curious. This has led me to teaching myself how to code and becoming a Software Developer with 3 years of industry experience. I am now looking to work with technology that gets me excited along with projects that deliver real value. And, hopefully, all while being alongside fun, likeminded peers.

Experience

Sandfield — Software Developer

Jan 2020 – Jan 2022

- Developed full-stack features within Sandfield's largest web application involving SQL as the database layer with a C# backend together with an ASP.NET, HTML and JavaScript frontend.
- Refactored mobile app module leading to an increase in client usage from low 20% to 90%+. This
 involved a complete remodelling of the UI as well as migrating the frontend data store from WebSQL to
 IndexedDB.

Sandfield — Software Developer Intern

Sep 2018 – Jan 2020

- Created full suite of automated tests using Selenium to handle regression testing that was demonstrated and delivered to the client as part of a project.
- Created CPU logging charts using Highcharts library which are now being used to monitor internal processes at the company.
- Carried out research tasks that led to a write up of a project proposal which was proposed to the client.

Skills: ASP.NET, MS SQL, C#, JavaScript, AJAX, HTML, (S)CSS, jQuery, Selenium, Agile, MVC

Education

BE (Honours) Mechatronics Engineering — The University of Auckland

Mar 2015 – May 2020

Skills: C/C++, C#, MATLAB, Arduino, LabVIEW, Quartus, R, PTC Creo 3.0

Personal Projects

Google Drive Clone — https://mygoogledriveclone.netlify.app/

June 2022

- Developed using **React** frontend with a **Firebase** datastore.
- Implemented a user creation and login which gets stored in a database alongside any files that user uploads.
- Allows users to upload files and create folders like Google Drive.

Skills: React, React Hooks + Custom Hooks, Contexts, Portals, Routers, Firebase

Yelp Clone — https://yelperia.com/

May 2022

- Refactored older version written with **React** classes to use functional **React**.
- Allows users to search for businesses in specified locations, using Yelp API.
- Added geolocation to use of the user's location to allow for local searching with ease.
- Added data pagination with infinite scrolling to allow for faster data requests.

Skills: React, React Hooks + Custom Hooks